<?xml version='1.0'?>
<CodeNarc url='http://www.codenarc.org' version='0.21'><Report timestamp='Oct 2, 2014 6:16:24 PM'/><Project title='Repose Components - Client Authentication'><SourceDirectory>src/test/groovy</SourceDirectory></Project><PackageSummary totalFiles='1' filesWithViolations='0' priority1='0' priority2='0' priority3='0'></PackageSummary><Package path='' totalFiles='1' filesWithViolations='0' priority1='0' priority2='0' priority3='0'></Package><Rules><Rule name='Blanks around method'><Description><![CDATA[No description provided for rule named [Blanks around method]]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='BracesForClass'><Description><![CDATA[Checks the location of the opening brace ({) for classes. By default, requires them on the same line, but the sameLine property can be set to false to override this.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='BracesForForLoop'><Description><![CDATA[Checks the location of the opening brace ({) for for loops. By default, requires them on the same line, but the sameLine property can be set to false to override this.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='BracesForIfElse'><Description><![CDATA[Checks the location of the opening brace ({) for if statements. By default, requires them on the same line, but the sameLine property can be set to false to override this.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='BracesForMethod'><Description><![CDATA[Checks the location of the opening brace ({) for constructors and methods. By default, requires them on the same line, but the sameLine property can be set to false to override this.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='BracesForTryCatchFinally'><Description><![CDATA[Checks the location of the opening brace ({) for try statements. By default, requires them on the line, but the sameLine property can be set to false to override this.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='Max 2 blank lines before }'><Description><![CDATA[No description provided for rule named [Max 2 blank lines before }]]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='Require space before and after a :'><Description><![CDATA[No description provided for rule named [Require space before and after a :]]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='Require space before and after a ?'><Description><![CDATA[No description provided for rule named [Require space before and after a ?]]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='Require space before else, catch, or finally'><Description><![CDATA[No description provided for rule named [Require space before else, catch, or finally]]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterCatch'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is exactly one space (blank) after the catch keyword and before the opening parenthesis.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterComma'><Description><![CDATA[Checks that there is at least one space or whitespace following each comma. That includes checks for method and closure declaration parameter lists, method call parameter lists, Map literals and List literals.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterFor'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is exactly one space (blank) after the for keyword and before the opening parenthesis.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterIf'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is exactly one space (blank) after the if keyword and before the opening parenthesis.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterOpeningBrace'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is at least one space (blank) or whitespace after each opening brace ("{") for method/class/interface declarations, closure expressions and block statements.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterSemicolon'><Description><![CDATA[Checks that there is at least one space or whitespace following each semicolon separating multiple statements on a single line or the clauses within a classic for loop.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterSwitch'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is exactly one space (blank) after the switch keyword and before the opening parenthesis.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAfterWhile'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is exactly one space (blank) after the while keyword and before the opening parenthesis.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceAroundOperator'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is at least one space (blank) or whitespace around each binary operator.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceBeforeClosingBrace'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is at least one space (blank) or whitespace before each closing brace ("}") for method/class/interface declarations, closure expressions and block statements.]]></Description></Rule><Rule name='SpaceBeforeOpeningBrace'><Description><![CDATA[Check that there is at least one space (blank) or whitespace before each opening brace ("{") for method/class/interface declarations, closure expressions and block statements.]]></Description></Rule></Rules></CodeNarc>