<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<suppressions xmlns="https://jeremylong.github.io/DependencyCheck/dependency-suppression.1.2.xsd">
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: echo-filter.jar (project :repose-aggregator:components:filters:echo-filter)
            NOTE: This is simply a case of mistaken identity.
            The echo-filter used for internal testing has the same name as a known vulnerable filter.
        ]]></notes>
        <cpe>cpe:/a:echo_project:echo</cpe>
    </suppress>
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: xz-1.0.jar
            NOTE: This is simply a case of mistaken identity.
            The Java version of this library is not afflicted with this particular vulnerability.
        ]]></notes>
        <gav regex="true">^org\.tukaani:xz:.*$</gav>
        <cve>CVE-2015-4035</cve>
    </suppress>
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: jetty-6.1.26.jar
            NOTE: There is a transitive dependency with a known vulnerability exists, but it is not exposed.
            The Log4J Flume Appender is an event driven Flume Source that is supported by the Highly Efficient Record Processor (HERP) filter to send event data to a remote Flume Agent.
            The Log4J Flume Appender is not pollable even though it depends on the flume-ng-sdk which does support that type of source.
            Therefore the transitive dependency on an old Jetty version with a known vulnerability that is used to support polling does not expose the potential DOS attack vector in this instance.
        ]]></notes>
        <gav regex="true">^org\.mortbay\.jetty:jetty:.*$</gav>
        <cve>CVE-2011-4461</cve>
    </suppress>
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: jython-standalone-2.7.1.jar (shaded: com.google.guava:guava:22.0-android)
            NOTE: This is being fixed under issue https://bugs.jython.org/issue2728
            This is currently only potentially exposed if the Scripting filter is used with Python to deserialize certain data types.
        ]]></notes>
        <gav regex="true">^com\.google\.guava:guava:.*$</gav>
        <cve>CVE-2018-10237</cve>
    </suppress>
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: json-patch-1.6.jar
            NOTE: The dependency which includes this issue is a transitive dependency inherited from com.atlassian.oai:swagger-request-validator-core.
            The issue in question appears to be in a different JSON patching library written in Go and used by OpenShift.
            In other words, this appears to be a case of mistaken identity.
        ]]></notes>
        <gav regex="true">^com\.github\.fge:json-patch:.*$</gav>
        <cve>CVE-2018-14632</cve>
    </suppress>
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: slf4j-ext-1.6.3.jar
            NOTE: The dependency which includes this issue is a transitive dependency inherited from com.atlassian.oai:swagger-request-validator-core.
            The issue in question is in the constructor of the EventData class, which is never invoked by Repose or any of its transitive dependencies.
            As such, this issue is inaccessible to Repose users.
        ]]></notes>
        <gav regex="true">^org\.slf4j:slf4j-ext:.*$</gav>
        <cve>CVE-2018-8088</cve>
    </suppress>
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: jetty-(servlet|security|server|http|util)-9.4.14.v20181114.jar
            NOTE: This vulnerability is only exposed if the DefaultServlet or ResourceHandler are used with indexing/listing enabled.
            Since Repose doesn't use these normally default classes, this issue does not effect Repose users.
        ]]></notes>
        <gav regex="true">^org\.eclipse\.jetty:jetty-(?:servlet|security|server|http|util):.*$</gav>
        <cve>CVE-2019-10241</cve>
        <cve>CVE-2019-10246</cve>
        <cve>CVE-2019-10247</cve>
    </suppress>
    <suppress>
        <notes><![CDATA[
            file name: jackson-databind-2.9.9.jar
            NOTE: There is currently no remediation for this vulnerability and no alternatives exist.
            Additionally we don't utilize any of the affected functionality.
        ]]></notes>
        <gav regex="true">^com\.fasterxml\.jackson\.core:jackson-databind:.*$</gav>
        <cve>CVE-2019-12814</cve>
    </suppress>
</suppressions>
